<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Patrick Childs | Academic</title><link>/author/patrick-childs/</link><atom:link href="/author/patrick-childs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Patrick Childs</description><generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 May 2019 21:54:29 -0400</lastBuildDate><image><url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url><title>Patrick Childs</title><link>/author/patrick-childs/</link></image><item><title>Flatfail</title><link>/post/flatfail/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2019 21:54:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>/post/flatfail/</guid><description>&lt;p>So after re-installing fedora and having some trouble with firejail, which is discussed further here, I decided to try out flatpak&amp;rsquo;s sandboxing features. After having done what I always do with new security solutions, try to break it, I discovered that there are many flaws inherent in flatpak&amp;rsquo;s approach to security.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="what-is-flatpak">What is flatpak&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Flatpak is self-described as &amp;ldquo;The future of apps on Linux&amp;rdquo;, and is a new-age application manager developed mainly by RedHat. It tries to take the Android/iOS approach to application isolation, where each application is sandboxed, and permission has to be requested and approved by the user. It tries to achieve this through sandboxing applications using Linux Namespaces, and limiting Kernel calls available to the application.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-not-to-make-a-sandbox">How not to make a Sandbox&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Sandboxes are supposed to restrict access to a system in various ways, such that a sandboxed application is isolated from the rest of the system. In principle, these can be incredibly powerful, providing comprehensive protections from malicious code. The main benefit of this, is not to run un-trusted code, but to prevent exploited applications from pivoting, or maintaining persistence.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s inherently hard to escape a sandbox, in fact sandbox escapes are quite valuable as exploits. That being said, a sandbox is only as strong as it&amp;rsquo;s policies. If a sandbox does not properly police access, it can be trivial to escape. So it&amp;rsquo;s incredibly important to make sure policies are properly setup.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is where Flatpak&amp;rsquo;s first mistake is made, almost all major applications have write access to a user&amp;rsquo;s home directory, leaving many opportunities to escape the sandbox. Writing to &lt;code>.bashrc&lt;/code> or &lt;code>.profile&lt;/code> can provide a method of privilege escalation&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Simple Opsec</title><link>/post/simple-opsec/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/simple-opsec/</guid><description>&lt;p>This website looks very bare, not many projects and posts. There&amp;rsquo;s a big reason why it&amp;rsquo;s so empty, Opsec.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve spent a lot of my life protecting my identities from a real life counterpart. Thus protecting me from fallout of my poor decisions in my youth. Now that I&amp;rsquo;m in my 20s, and looking for work, I do need an identity closely tied to my real life identity. So this identity was created to facilitate that, so that I can still provide personal details publicly without cross contaminating with other identities.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thus this identity, and by extension this website does not have much content. All my achievements are strewn across various identities.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While this Identity isn&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em>that&lt;/em> new, it&amp;rsquo;s not been utilized much. I&amp;rsquo;m going to start using it more for projects that don&amp;rsquo;t require separation of identities.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So hopefully this website will be more appealing to employers in the near future.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hello Hugo</title><link>/post/hello-world/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/hello-world/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hello, this is a very simple post to say that this website is now working. Built with hugo and the Academic hugo theme.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s very simple, hosted on github pages.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>